{"tossups": [{"question": "The criminal \u201cSoapy\u201d Smith\u201d ran organized crime in Colorado and what is now this state, where he died. With Louisiana, this is the only U.S. state that does not have counties. Over a hundred people died in this state during the 1964 Good Friday earthquake, which triggered tsunamis that killed five people in Oregon. The purchase of this future state, at the price of 2 cents per acre, was dubbed \u201cSeward\u2019s Folly.\u201dFor the point, what future state was bought from Russia in 1867?", "answer": "<b> Alaska</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This country occupied a neighbor after the 1969 Act of Free Choice. One leader of this nation coined the term \u201cnasakom\u201d to describe a nationalist ideology that appeased communists, then instituted \u201cGuided Democracy\u201d in 1957. The New Order ousted that leader of this country, which occupied East Timor until a 1999 referendum. Sukarno and Suharto ruled, for the point, what Asian archipelagic nation that controls the island of Java and has its capital at Jakarta?", "answer": "Republic of<b> Indonesia</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "The most populous county in this state was originally named for Franklin Pierce\u2019s vice president, but was rededicated in 1986 to a civil rights leader with the same last name. A structure in this state, which connected the Kitsap Peninsula to its namesake city, collapsed due to aerostatic flutter in 1940 and was nicknamed \u201cGalloping Gertie.\u201d The Puget Sound was traversed by the Tacoma Narrows Bridge in, for the point, what state, where King County contains the city of Seattle?", "answer": "<b> Washington</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "Sticky prices were initially explained during the tail end of the Great Depression by positing a\u201ckinked\u201d variety of this concept. The<em> y</em>-axis of a Keynesian cross shows one form of this quantity. While a good\u2019s utility may determine the price, this concept is theoretically only determined by income. For the point, name this economic quantity that represents the willingness of consumers to consume, a concept often contrasted with supply.", "answer": "<b> demand</b> (curve)", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Economics"}, {"question": "Chalcuchimac [chal-coo-chee-mak] helped recapture Tumipampa for this empire during the War of the Two Brothers. After insultingly throwing a Bible to the ground, one ruler from this empire was captured at Cajamarca [ca-ha-mar-ka] and ransomed for a room full of gold. Huascar\u2019s rival, Atahualpa, ruled this empire but was unable to stop Francisco Pizarro\u2019s conquistadors. For the point, name this South American empire whose cities included Cuzco and Machu Picchu in modern Peru.", "answer": "<b> Inca</b>n Empire", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "During this war, the<em> C-3</em> was sunk in Operation Ursula, a mostly-unsuccessful attempt at submarine warfare. This war\u2019s victors enjoyed the support of Moroccan forces and were supported by the Carlists. The term \u201cfifth column\u201d was coined during this war, in which the German Condor Legion bombed Guernica, an atrocity immortalized by Pablo Picasso. For the point, name this war in which the Falangists rose to power under Francisco Franco in an Iberian country.", "answer": "<b> Spanish Civil</b> War", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "The League of Augsburg formed after this king\u2019s interference in the Rhineland. This king received a Siamese diplomatic mission from King Narai of Ayutthaya. His finance minister Colbert greatly increased tax revenue, and this king withdrew protection of Protestants by revoking the Edict of Nantes. His proclamation that \u201cI am the state\u201d exemplified his control of an absolute monarchy centered at Versailles. For the point, name this Sun King of France.", "answer": "<b> Louis XIV</b> (prompt on Sun King until mentioned)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "This empire rose to power after the fall of the Mthethwa [m\u2019thay-thwa] Empire. These people were unable to capture Rorke\u2019s Drift despite a massive numerical advantage. This empire equipped its warriors with the iklwa spear and cowhide shields and won the Battle of Isandlwana while led by Cetshwayo. A king of these people developed the impi units and created the buffalo horn formation. The British conquered, for the point, what South African empire that was united by Shaka?", "answer": "<b> Zulu</b> Empire (or ama<b>Zulu</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "During the first of these conflicts, the corvus, a plank designed to board ships, was developed. Fabius developed a delaying strategy during the second one of these wars after an opponent won the Battle of Cannae with a massive envelopment. Cato\u2019s repeated insistence that a city must be destroyed helped spark the third and last of these wars. Hannibal Barca crossed the Alps with elephants during the second of, for the point, what wars fought between Rome and Carthage?", "answer": "<b> Punic</b> Wars", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "For the point, name the first leader of the Soviet Union.", "answer": "VIadimir Ilyich<b> Lenin</b> (or Vladimir Ilyich<b> Ulyanov</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This city\u2019s mayor, George Moscone, was killed by disgruntled city supervisor Dan White, who used the controversial \u201cTwinkie defense\u201d at his trial. The United Nations charter was signed in this city, which was once led by Mayor Dianne Feinstein. The \u201cSummer of Love\u201d featured hippies converging on this city\u2019s Haight-Ashbury neighborhood. Gay rights activist Harvey Milk was killed in, for the point, what California city that was devastated by a 1906 earthquake?", "answer": "<b> San Francisco</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "One government of this nation martyred peace activist V\u00b4\u0131ctor Jara. This country fully nationalized its copper mines in 1971 and kept them under state control, even as the \u201cChicago Boys\u201d promoted free market policies that led to this country\u2019s economic \u201cmiracle.\u201d In 1973, the CIA helped depose a democratically elected Marxist in, for the point, what South American nation where Salvador Allende [ah-yen-day] overthrew Augusto Pinochet [pin-oh-shay]?", "answer": "<b> Chile</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "During this war, the U.S. army gave preference to Chicago meatpackers over local cattle, so Nelson Miles\u2019 soldiers suffered through shipments of \u201cembalmed beef.\u201d Frederic Remington was allegedly told to\u201cfurnish the pictures\u201d so that William Hearst could \u201cfurnish\u201d this war through yellow journalism. George Dewey\u2019s victory at Manila Bay clinched the Pacific theater of, for the point, what war that was prompted by the sinking of the USS<em> Maine</em> in Havana Harbor?", "answer": "<b> Spanish-American</b> War", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "The protagonist of this novel feels justified in running away after seeing a squirrel run away from his tossed pine cone. The protagonist of this novel attempts to distance himself from a \u201ctattered soldier\u201d who asks him where he was hit. This novel\u2019s depiction of fighting in a forest is often compared to the Battle of Chancellorsville. Jim Conklin dies after refusing medical care in, for the point, what Civil War novel about the young, scared soldier Henry Fleming, written by Stephen Crane?", "answer": "The<b> Red Badge of Courage</b>", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Short Fiction"}, {"question": "After the end of these wars, Perkin Warbeck and Lambert Simnel both pretended to be one of the Princes in the Tower. Richard Neville was known as the Kingmaker during these wars that ended at the Battle of Bosworth Field. These wars ended with the ascension of Henry VII Tudor, a member of the House of Lancaster, who married a daughter of the House of York, the two rival houses that fought these wars. For the point, name these wars fought for the English throne named for a certain flower.", "answer": "Wars of the<b> Roses</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "In July, this country\u2019s internal security chief, Patrick Calvar, warned that another terrorist attack could plunge this country into \u201cprolonged civil conflict.\u201d The far right National Front led by Marine Le Pen has grown in this country, which has been in a state of emergency since the November 2015 attacks, which included a shooting at the Bataclan Theatre. For the point, name this country that was targeted by ISIS supporters during Bastille Day celebrations in Nice [\u201dniece\u201d].", "answer": "<b> France</b>", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "A practitioner of this religion assassinated a political leader at the Birla House for having advocated the creation of Pakistan. Members of this religion are traditionally divided into four castes as part of the Varna system, which excludes the \u201cuntouchables.\u201d During this religion\u2019s Kumbh Mela festival, millions of adherents wash away their sin in the Ganges River. Shiva, Vishnu, and Brahma form the Trimurti in, for the point, what most prevalent religion in India?", "answer": "<b> Hindu</b>ism", "metadata": "Religion - Religion"}, {"question": "This political party used Mefo bills to finance its economic programs, including militarization. The White Rose movement opposed this political party, which signed an Anti-Comintern pact with Japan in 1936. It purged its paramilitary, the SA, during the Night of the Long Knives, and sponsored a night of looting called the Night of Broken Glass in November 1938, burning dozens of synagogues. For the point, name this fascist party that ruled Germany\u2019s Third Reich until the end of World War II.", "answer": "<b> Nazi</b> Party (accept<b> National Socialist</b> German Workers\u2019 Party or<b> NSDAP</b>; accept<b> Nazi </b>Germany; do not accept or prompt on socialism alone)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "A disaster in this state was blamed on the failure of the South Fork Fishing and Hunting Club to maintain a dam. A businessman in this state, Henry Clay Frick, fought strikers who were challenging a company owned by the author of \u201cThe Gospel of Wealth.\u201d Over 2,000 people died in the 1889 Johnstown Flood in this state, which was also where the 1892 Homestead Strike took place. For the point, name this state where Carnegie Steel was founded in Pittsburgh.", "answer": "<b> Pennsylvania</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This country\u2019s north and south were once ruled by the Nanyue and Champa people, respectively. In the first century AD, the Trung Sisters rebelled against Chinese control of what is now this country. The French were removed from power over this country after they lost the Battle of Dien Bien Phu, leaving a country split at the 17th parallel between an American-supported South and Communist North. For the point, name this southeast Asian country whose Communist revolutionaries were led by Ho Chi Minh.", "answer": "<b> Vietnam</b> (accept North and/or South<b> Vietnam</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "This dynasty created the Grand Secretariat to oversee the Six Ministries. This dynasty allied with the Joseon during the Imjin War, and it was founded when the Hongwu emperor led the Red Turban Rebellion. The Yongle Emperor expanded the examination system and moved his capital to Beijing during this dynasty, which constructed the Grand Canal and the Forbidden City and sponsored Zheng He\u2019s voyages. The Yuan dynasty preceded, for the point, what Chinese dynasty known for exporting porcelain vases?", "answer": "<b> Ming</b> Dynasty", "metadata": "History - World History"}], "bonuses": []}